<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: macbook pro | andreanisme ★ net | Andrean Saputro]]></title>
  <link href="http://andreanisme.github.io/log/macbook-pro/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andreanisme.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-01T20:10:51+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://andreanisme.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrean Saputro]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[andreanisme@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Backing up my Ipod Nano]]></title>
    <link href="http://andreanisme.github.io/backing-up-my-ipod-nano/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-08T20:15:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://andreanisme.github.io/backing-up-my-ipod-nano</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the Eid holiday this time I have enough time to finish some work that I have not been completed because of busy work.</p>

<p>In addition to completing <em>andreanisme.net</em> with Octopress as I described in <a href="http://andreanisme.net/log/olleh-dlrow/">my previous post</a>. I intend to revive the 5th Generation iPod Nano that I get from the <a href="http://blog.andreanisme.com/archives/461">affiliate links in 2009</a>. Wait a minute, why be revived? I did not bring my iPod when I decided to Jakarta to work (about 6 months ago). And after in Jakarta, I miss with my iPod and I thought to bring it to Jakarta after I returned home on the Eid holiday.</p>

<p>Holidays have arrived, and I found my iPod is still in the same place — at the computer desk drawer. But my iPod will not turn on. Naturally, the battery runs out because the iPod was never filled in a fairly long period of time. I plugged the iPod connector into my Macbook Pro to do the charging. After 1 minute, the Apple logo appeared on my iPod and iTunes detects the device it supports.</p>

<h3>Having backups of my favorite song is a must!</h3>

<p>After half an hour, I saw the songs what is in my iPod. I met a few playlists of my favorite musicians, including: Mr. Big, Scorpions, Queen, Guns n Roses, Gugun Blues Shelter, Dewa 19, and many more.</p>

<p>But I intend to replaces the existing songs on my iPod playlist with some newer. While not all the songs will be replaced, limited storage capacity of 8 GB iPod requires me to sort the songs.</p>

<p>Some songs on my iPod are the songs that I transfers from my old PC. Worse! My PC can no longer be turned on due to damaged hard drive. So it is very important for me to get a backup from my collection of favorite songs.</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3739/9442057100_1ae5d2e466_c.jpg">http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3739/9442057100_1ae5d2e466_c.jpg</a>" title="&lsquo;Backing up my iPod Nano&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>I am looking for a way to backup iPod to the Macbook Pro. Of course through the Google search. There are several ways and tools that can be used for backup. I tried several apps, there are a total of 3 applications for Mac that I am trying. But eventually the applications I use is <a href="http://www.imacsoft.com/ipod-to-pc-transfer.html">Imacsoft iPod to PC Transfer</a>. There are free and paid version ($ 24 for a license price). I decided to use the free version only, with limited backing 99 list of songs in one process (batch processing). With limited free version of this application, I actually enjoy the process of sorting while looking back at my music collection on the iPod and determine which will be maintained in iPod or not!</p>

<p>Finally, I get the backup of my songs on my iPod, and they can be played in iTunes on my Macbook Pro. Of all the songs, I mark the &ldquo;Bossanova Jawa&rdquo; album as my favorite one. Since I was born and grew up in Solo — my hometown — which has thick Javanese tradition. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
